<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<Filipino-Foodie>

<home>

<food>Arroz Caldo</food>
   <title>Arros Caldo</title>
   <content>With Spanish and Chinese influences, arroz caldo is a great choice if 
   you are looking for healthy food in Philippines. The name of this wonderful dish 
   literally translates to ‘rice soup’ in English. Similar to the congee of Vietnam, 
   arroz caldo is a rice and chicken porridge stewed in broth, chives, ginger, and 
   occasionally, saffron. If you want a dish that has a soothing effect on your 
   stomach and offers health benefits, there is nothing better than a bowl of 
   delicious arroz caldo. </content>

<food>Adobo</food>
   <title>Adobo</title>
   <content>No list of the top 10 Filipino foods can begin without the famous Adobo on 
   top. The unofficial Philippines national food is made with pork or chicken simmered 
   in soy sauce and vinegar with loads of black pepper and crushed garlic. Adobo is one 
   of the few dishes in the Philippines with local origins as it was given the Spanish 
   name later. This lip-smacking dish is as Filipino as you can get, and it goes with 
   nothing else but rice. Every family in the Philippines has its own way of cooking adobo, 
   so it might taste a little different from place to place.</content>

<food>Sisig</food>
   <title>Sisig</title>
   <content>Sisig is a Filipino dish made from parts of a pig's face and belly, and chicken 
   liver which is usually seasoned with calamansi, onions, and chili peppers. It originates 
   from the Pampanga region in Luzon.Sisig is a staple of Kapampangan cuisine. The city 
   government of Angeles, Pampanga, through City Ordinance No. 405, series of 2017, declared 
   sizzling sisig babi ("pork sisig") as a tangible heritage of Angeles City.</content>

<food>Lumpia</food>
   <title>Lumpia</title>
   <content>Feel like tasting Filipino dishes for lunch? Try Lumpia. Influenced by Chinese 
   cuisine, this dish is a delicious deep-fried spring roll. The roll is stuffed with a 
   mixture of chopped vegetables and minced meat. Combined with the right sauces, it is the 
   most scrumptious dish you will ever have for lunch. This is definitely a traditional Filipino 
   dish after trying which, you will never look at spring rolls the same way again. It is a major 
   part of Philippines food culture.</content>

<food>Pansit</food>
   <title>Pansit</title>
   <content>Also known as Pancit, this is another one of the most delicious Philippines foods 
   influenced by Chinese cuisine. This simple dish is a combination of noodles and whatever meat 
   or vegetables you want to add. Pancit is a name that originated from the Hokkien term ‘pian e 
   sit’, which means ‘something conveniently cooked.’ It might be simple but it is rich with flavor 
   and you will definitely love every bite of it.</content>

<food>Sinigang</food>
   <title>Sinigang</title>
   <content>Often associated with tamarind, Sinigang is a Philippines traditional food that is sour 
   and savory. The dish is a stew made with spinach, eggplant, tomatoes, onions, ginger, and fish sauce. 
   You can choose the meat you want to make the dish with pork, beef, fish, or shrimp. No matter which 
   one you choose, the result is always a mouthwatering stew served with rice or eaten on its own as soup. </content>

<food>Lechon</food>
   <title>Lechon</title>
   <content>When it comes to popular Philippines food items present at every special occasion, lechon 
   is probably one of the top ones. This is another dish with Spanish influence and no fiesta in the 
   country is complete unless there is enough lechon for everyone.This dish is roast suckling pig that 
   is cooked to perfection. Everyone loves the delicious crunchy skin. If you want to taste one of the 
   most popular authentic Filipino dishes, you should definitely look for a place that serves traditional 
   lechon. </content>

<food>Cassava Cake</food>
   <title>Cassava Cake</title>
   <content>No list of the top 10 Filipino foods can begin without the famous Adobo on top. The unofficial 
   Philippines national food is made with pork or chicken simmered in soy sauce and vinegar with loads of 
   black pepper and crushed garlic.Adobo is one of the few dishes in the Philippines with local origins as 
   it was given the Spanish name later. This lip-smacking dish is as Filipino as you can get, and it goes 
   with nothing else but rice. Every family in the Philippines has its own way of cooking adobo, so it 
   might taste a little different from place to place. </content>

<food>Kare - kare</food>
   <title>Kare - kare</title>
   <content>Kare-kare is a Philippine stew (kare derives from "curry") that features a thick savory peanut 
   sauce. It is generally made from a base of stewed oxtail, beef tripe, pork hocks, calves feet, pig's 
   feet or trotters, various cuts of pork, beef stew meat, and occasionally offal. Vegetables, such as 
   eggplant, Chinese cabbage, or other greens, daikon, green beans, okra, and asparagus beans, are added.
   The stew is flavored with ground roasted peanuts or peanut butter, onions, and garlic. It is colored with
    annatto and can be thickened with toasted or plain ground rice. Variations of kare-kare can be made 
   with seafood, such as (prawns, squid, and mussels, or exclusively from vegetables. Condiments and other 
   flavorings are usually added. It is often eaten with bagoong (shrimp paste), sometimes spiced with chili, 
   ginisáng bagoóng (spiced and sautéed shrimp paste), and sprinkled with calamansi juice. Other seasonings are 
   added at the table. Variants may include goat meat or (rarely) chicken.</content>

<food>Dinuguan with puto</food>
   <title>Dinuguan with Puto</title>
   <content>Dinuguan at puto is considered as a good meal combination for most Filipinos. This refers to pork 
    stew and steamed rice cake. The pork is sauteed in garlic and onions. Water, vinegar, and pork blood are 
    added and then cooked until it becomes nice and thick. It is best eaten by dipping (or scooping) the blood 
    stew using steamed rice cake (or what is called puto in Filipino) and eating both together.</content>

<food>Bicol Express</food>
   <title>Bicol Express</title>
   <content>Feel like tasting Filipino dishes for lunch? Try Lumpia. Influenced by Chinese cuisine, this dish 
   is a delicious deep-fried spring roll. The roll is stuffed with a mixture of chopped vegetables and minced 
   meat. Combined with the right sauces, it is the most scrumptious dish you will ever have for lunch. This is 
   definitely a traditional Filipino dish after trying which, you will never look at spring rolls the same way 
   again. It is a major part of Philippines food culture.</content>

<food>Halo - halo</food>
   <title>Halo - halo</title>
   <content>Halo-halo, officially spelled haluhalo, Tagalog for "mixed," is a popular cold dessert in the Philippines 
   made up of crushed ice, evaporated milk or coconut milk, and various ingredients including ube jam (ube halaya), 
   sweetened kidney or garbanzo beans, coconut strips, sago, gulaman (agar), pinipig, boiled taro or soft yams in cubes, 
   flan, slices or portions of fruit preserves and other root crop preserves.The dessert is topped with a scoop of ube 
   or mango ice cream. It is usually prepared in a tall clear glass and served with a long spoon. Halo-halo is considered 
   to be the unofficial national dessert of the Philippines. The term "halo-halo" translates to "mixed" in English because 
   the dessert is meant to be mixed before being consumed. This spelling has come to describe any object or situation composed 
   of a similar, colorful combination of ingredients.</content>

<food>Taho</food>
   <title>Taho</title>
   <content>Tahô is a Philippine snack food made of fresh soft/silken tofu, arnibal, and sago pearl. This staple comfort food is 
   a signature sweet and tahô peddlers can be found all over the country. </content>

<food>Suman</food>
   <title>Suman</title>
   <content>Suman or budbud is a rice cake originating in the Philippines. It is made from glutinous rice cooked in coconut milk, 
   often wrapped in banana leaves, coconut leaves, or buli or buri palm leaves for steaming. It is usually eaten sprinkled with 
   sugar or laden with latik.</content>

<food>Chicharrón</food>
   <title>Chicharrón</title>
   <content>Chicharon, less commonly spelled tsitsaron, is ubiquitous, as it is a well-loved snack, and may be bought anywhere, 
   from large supermarket chains to small neighborhood sari-sari stores and street vendors. It is popular as pulutan or tapas 
   food to be eaten while consuming alcoholic beverages. It is also used as a topping on many native vegetable and noodle dishes. 
   Pork chicharon is prepared by deep-frying dried pork rind with a little salt. It may be dipped in coconut vinegar spiced with 
   soy sauce, chopped garlic and labuyo chili peppers, or eaten with other condiments like bagoong anchovies, lechon gravy sauce, 
   or atchara papaya salad. Aside from pork rind, chicken skin may also be made into chicharong manok, whereas chicharong 
   bulaklak—literally 'flower chicharrón', named for its distinctive shape—is made from pig offal. Tuna-skin chicharon 
   is marketed as a healthier variation. In Cagayan, water buffalo hide is used to make "carabao chicharon". A distinct 
   variant of chicharon involves cooking pork loin and meat in the same way, becoming bagnet. While similar and dissimilar 
   to crispy pata, it is more popular as a meal than finger food, and has found its way to contemporary dishes and restaurants. 
   Bagnet originates from Ilocos where it has been served since the 1960s.</content>

<food>Balut</food>
   <title>Balut</title>
   <content>Feel like tasting Filipino dishes for lunch? Try Lumpia. Influenced by Chinese cuisine, this dish is a delicious 
   deep-fried spring roll. The roll is stuffed with a mixture of chopped vegetables and minced meat. Combined with the right 
   sauces, it is the most scrumptious dish you will ever have for lunch. This is definitely a traditional Filipino dish after 
   trying which, you will never look at spring rolls the same way again. It is a major part of Philippines food culture.</content>

<food>Torta</food>
   <title>Torta</title>
   <content>Torta is another Filipino dish with roots in Spain. In Spanish cuisine, it is a general term that 
   refers to many different dishes. Within Filipino cuisine, it refers to omelets. Torta has scrambled eggs and 
   other ingredients, including ground meat and vegetables. Many restaurants offer their own styles of torta. 
   Tortang Alimasag is akin to crab cakes, containing egg and sauteed crab meat served inside the crab shells. 
   You can eat torta for breakfast. But you can find it for lunch, served with salad or fried potatoes. This 
   Torta recipe is perfect to try at home.</content>

<food>Leche Flan</food>
   <title>Leche Flan</title>
   <content>Leche Flan is one of the most beloved and popular desserts in the Philippines. The word “leche” 
   means milk in Spanish and leche flan is a local term derived from the original Spanish leche de flan, 
   which means milk flan. Egg whites were used in the building of churches during the Spanish colonial era, 
   and the egg yolks leftover did not to go to waste.A dessert was made out of them, which is now known as 
   leche flan, otherwise known as crème caramel. The Philippine leche flan is a much heavier version of the 
   original recipe, using more egg yolks and condensed milk. This special treat is served on all special 
   occasions. It is a simple yet decadent dessert with a luscious caramel on top. It melts in your mouth 
   and has a rich, silky, smooth and creamy custard texture.</content>


<food>Batchoy</food>
   <title>Batchoy</title>
   <content>Batchoy is a noodle soup. It is extremely popular in La Paz, but you can find it throughout 
   the country. Chefs prepare it with egg noodles in a pork and beef broth. They then put in pieces of pork, 
   including chopped pork liver. La Paz Batchoy can contain additional ingredients. Chefs in La Paz like to 
   put in fried garlic and raw eggs. You mix the eggs into the soup, and they cook inside the broth. Batchoy 
   tagalog is another popular variant. It has misua noodles, which are salted and very thin. The broth is 
   ginger-based instead of animal-based, but the soup can contain pieces of pork in it.</content>

<food>Sapin - sapin</food>
   <title>Sapin - sapin</title>
   <content>Made with galapong (glutinous rice dough), coconut milk, sugar, condensed milk, and an occasional 
   ube or jackfruit flavoring, this festive and colorful dish has a dense, chewy pudding-like texture, and is 
   often seen at social gatherings or festive occasions. This colorful delicacy is very time-consuming to make. 
   The process starts with making the sticky rice dough from scratch, then extracting the coconut milk and cooking 
   ube halaya which is one of its many layers. It usually takes a whole day to finish this dessert. Sapin-Sapin is 
   a festive looking dessert with vibrant colors and is usually served with latik or toasted coconut curd. It is 
   visually appealing and typically has 3 layers; purple, yellow, and white.</content>

<food>Liempo</food> 
   <title>Liempo</title>
   <content>Easy Liempo Inihaw is a type of pork barbecue. It is grilled the Filipino way. Liempo or pork belly are 
   marinated in basic inihaw marinade composed of soy sauce, banana sauce, ground black pepper, and lemon 
   (or calamansi). A special liquid seasoning intentionally created as a marinade for meats is also used. This 
   ingredient makes this dish tastier. You will know more about it in the recipe below.</content>

<food>Buko Pandan</food>
   <title>Buko Pandan</title>
   <content>Buko Pandan is a popular Filipino Dessert made using young coconut, pandan leaves (or Screwpine leaves), 
   and sago pearls. At first glance, this dessert dish can be mistaken for Buko Salad. Both desserts are almost similar 
   visually. The dish is composed of a sweet and creamy concoction. Condensed milk, all-purpose cream, and strings of 
   young coconut are the main components. Sago pearls can also be added.</content>
</home>


<about>
<about>About us</about>
</about>


<services>
<svc>Satisfaction</svc>
    <content>We provide happiness to the users. We help them share their culture and traditions through food so that 
    they can be proud of their places. We bring smiles to the faces of every user by giving them the best quality of 
    images. We improve our design so that we can satisfy and persuade the people to try the Filipino Foods.</conttent>

<svc>Wide range Network</svc>
<content>We provide a wide-reaching network where the food that you share can be seen by many people across the globe. 
We reach different countries to let the Filipino food to be known and for others to try it. Having this wide networking 
means that others can see the Filipino’s culture and tradition through their food.</content>

<svc>Update and Security</svc>
<content>We provide a tight security. The private information of our users can only be seen by a higher employee. Our 
website maintenance and security tasks have a regular basis to maintain the integrity of our website. We do updates and 
24/7 incoming filtering to block potential malware, DDoS attacks, cross-site scripting, and other unwanted intrusions 
that could affect the website’s integrity.</content>
</services>


<contact>
<con>+6393 0402 9635</con>
<con>filipinofoodie@gmail.com</con>
<con>Doña Aurora St. Mogpog, Marinduque</con>
</contact>

</Filipino-Foodie>